A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of the Vice President, Office Files of David Bell FA624
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Appendix A: Reports Accessioned
  - Wilhelm, Harry E. Activities of the Office for Latin America and the Caribbean in 1968, 1969 January (Report 7827)
  - Smock, David R. Addis Ababa University (680-0650)., 1978 December (Report 8914)
  - Ford Foundation. Adolescence: from explanation to program., 1977 February (Report 9204)
  - Ford Foundation. Africa, 1958 (Report 9016)
  - Hardin, Lowell S. Agricultural development in Latin America, 1966 August (Report 238)
  - ID/LAC. Agricultural program notes, 1967 September (Report 8987)
  - Ford Foundation. Agriculture, natural resources, and related rural development in developing countries, 1980 September (Report 5869)
  - Sutton, F., X. Aid and the problems of education, employment and rural development, 1966 September (Report 3063)
  - Cuninggim, Merrimon. "All our ways and means of work" and "Summaries of major reports and selected memoranda by Merrimon Cuninggim and Mary Brucker", 1975 March (Report 2789)
  - Bell, David E. Allocation of staff time and FAPs to direct charitable activities, 1971 November (Report 8832)
  - Kingsley, J. Donald. Annual report, FY65: Middle East and Africa Program, 1966 January (Report 9020)
  - Ford Foundation. Arid Lands Agricultural Development Program: program and budget for 1972 with projections through 1976, 1971 October (Report 7511)
  - Ford Foundation. The arts in June, 1977 June (Report 4539)
  - Barnett, Milton L. Aspects of the socio-economic environment of communal tension in Malaysia, 1970 April (Report 3792)
  - Ward, F. Champion. Assistance to education in the seventies, 1971 September (Report 3974)
  - Ward, F. C. Assisting educational and cultural development: a report on current planning and activity, 1976 September (Report 3924)
  - Ford Foundation. Balance of payments problem, 1965 March (Report 2787)
  - Ford Foundation. Basic policy planning: a discussion paper, 1964 April (Report 2793)
  - Bell, David E. Bellagio Conference on Health and Population in Developing Countries, April 18-21,1979, 1979 April (Report 9118)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Bellagio Conference on "Research and training priorities in international relations", May 6-10, 1974 May (Report 9048)
  - Bell, David E. Bellagio conference on "Social Science Research on Development", Feb. 13-15, 1974, 1974 March (Report 7032)
  - Bell/Harkavy. "Best ways to improve health in the LDCs", 1979 February (Report 9119)
  - Baer, Werner. The Brazilian boom: 1968 - 1972. An explanation and interpretation, 1973 (Report 8953)
  - Barber, Elinor G. The Brazilian women's program, 1980 April (Report 7860)
  - Newmann, John. The budget in 1980: a comment, 1974 July (Report 9008)
  - Bell, David E. Budget planning paper, FY 1974 - 75, International Division, 1973 February (Report 9010)
  - Hagler, Jon L. et al. Budget policy, investment policy, and uncertainty, 1977 December (Report 4138)
  - Kennedy, Roger D. Budget policy, investment policy, prudence, and risk, 1976 May (Report 4049)
  - Staples, Eugene S. Budget review, 1970 January (Report 8927)
  - Edwards, Robert H. Budgetary transition, 1974 September (Report 9011)
  - Kennedy, Roger D. Budgets, assets, and expectations, 1976 December (Report 3449)
  - Gamble, William K. Burma revisited: 19 years later, 1971 November (Report 8458)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Canadian Studies in the United States, 1971 March (Report 9029)
  - Ford Foundation. Central American program - discussion paper, 1963 September (Report 8956)
  - Silvert, Kalman H. Chile, 1974 March (Report 8959)
  - Bresnan, John. China, 1978 September (Report 9006)
  - Robinson, Marshall A. China and the Ford Foundation: an opening door, 1979 May (Report 9005)
  - Wang Gungwu. Chinese politics in Malaya, 1970 April (Report 3797)
  - Staples, Eugene S. Comments on Malaysia and Singapore, 1967 September (Report 9050)
  - Drysdale, Robert S. Comments on the Sutton-Soedjatmoko exchange of the closing session, 1979 March (Report 8923)
  - Ford Foundation. Communities and neighborhoods - a possible private sector initiative for the 1980s, 1979 January (Report 4123)
  - Ford Foundation. Conference of Ford Foundation overseas representatives, Beirut Lebanon, October 5-9, 1953 (Report 2483)
  - Ginsburg/Feldman/Bress. Conflict of interest, 1974 October (Report 9190)
  - Ford Foundation. Conflict resolution and regulation - another look (includes appendix), 1977 September (Report 4118)
  - Ford Foundation. Conflict resolution: prospects for the future, 1980 December (Report 6505)
  - Dressner, Howard R. Conflicts-of-interest (grant-making): a possible course of action, 1975 February (Report 9191)
  - Ford Foundation. The Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1966 June (Report 2784)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Consents to exclusive licenses under patents held by grantees: Mead Johnson and Alza, 1974 June (Report 9196)
  - Bell, David E. Consequences for the Foundation stemming from the Bellagio Conference on Population and Agriculture, April 5-9, 1970, 1970 April (Report 9122)
  - Lowenthal, Abraham, F. Consultant's report to the Ford Foundation's Mexico office, 1979 January (Report 8950)
  - Bell, David E. Consultative Group on International Agricultural Research. (Final report - CGIAR Review Committee), 1976 October (Report 8989)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Contraceptive development: legal, business, and policy issues, 1970 November (Report 4911)
  - Cunningham, James V. CORE proposal for Cleveland - evaluation of, 1967 April (Report 8847)
  - Kennedy, Roger G. Cost reductions in the investment operation, 1975 June (Report 9186)
  - Dye, Richard W. The crisis of communalism in Malaysia, 1970 March (Report 3794)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Curriculum for professionals dealing with rural women, 1980 December (Report 7839)
  - Ford Foundation. Delegated authority projects - guidelines, 1972 June (Report 8830)
  - Kelly/Silvert. Democratic policy and how it works, with special reference to the United States, 1975 December (Report 2195)
  - Dean Economics, Inc. Development indicator chart book, 1966 September (Report 3071)
  - Wickham, Robert S. The development potential of Mexico, Venezuela, and Central America, 1965 December (Report 108)
  - Stephens, Robert. Development problems in the Arab world, 1972 February (Report 1981)
  - Finkelstein, David. Developments in U.S.-China cultural exchanges, 1972 September (Report 9177)
  - Ward, Haskell G. Dialogue with South Africa, 1971 June (Report 8909)
  - McCloy, John J. Directives and terms of reference for the 1960s, 1962 June (Report 2795)
  - LeMelle, Wilbert J. Discussion at the University of Montreal, 1969 February (Report 9028)
  - Carmichael, William D. Discussion for the management workshop on staff composition, recruitment, and development, 1973 September (Report 7753)
  - Hardin, Lowell. Discussion materials on 1974 program and budget submissions: international agricultural research and training centers, 1973 June (Report 8995)
  - Ford Foundation. Discussion paper - a Foundation office in Europe, 1969 March (Report 9034)
  - Ford Foundation. Discussion paper - Overseas Development Program: South and Southeast Asia. Construction of the Foundation's office building in New Delhi, 1964 September (Report 2785)
  - Ford Foundation. Discussion paper - Program-related investments: Indonesia, 1971 September (Report 9076)
  - Ford Foundation. Discussion paper. Report of Committee on Citizen Education in World Affairs, 1965 February (Report 2581)
  - Robin/Rosser/Terzo. Discussion papers II and III - the International Urbanization Survey, 1971 (Report 5838)
  - Bell, David E. Discussions with human rights groups in Europe, 1976 May (Report 8839)
  - Bell, David. (Draft) discussion paper on the future of the Foundation's overseas development activities, 1966 November (Report 9013)
  - Bell/Berresford. Draft materials on expanded programs for women, 1980 February (Report 6263)
  - Heaps, David. Draft report on human rights, 1975 August (Report 5643)
  - Hatzfeldt, Hermann P. Economic development planning in Malaysia, 1970 March (Report 3,798)
  - Robinson, Marshall. Economics and the Ford Foundation - some background, 1979 January (Report 9111)
  - Ford Foundation. Education activities of the Ford Foundation: proposed program and budget for FY 1980 and FY 1981 (Report 9114)
  - Morse, Richard et al. Education in Colombia - Ford Foundation mission to Colombia, June 1960, 1961 (Report 13)
  - Ford Foundation. The Education program of the Ford Foundation, 1980 September (Report 5686)
  - Ashenfelter, O. et al. The Educational Opportunity Bank: the feasibility of a pilot project at the graduate level, 1970 November (Report 8846)
  - Edwards, E.O. Employment in developing countries, 1973 June (Report 2441)
  - (McPeak, William). Establishing an investment company that would enable private colleges and universities to increase the yield of their investments, 1954 (Report 8962)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. European trip with Roger Kennedy, 1972 January (Report 9043)
  - Boston Consulting Group. Evaluation of Henry Ford Hospital: a summary statement, 1972 September (Report 9178)
  - Gant, George F. Excerpts from the Government of Pakistan's preliminary evaluations of progress under its second Five-Year Plan, 1965 (Report 161)
  - Bell, David E. Expanded program activities concerning women, 1980 April (Report 8937)
  - Barber, Elinor G. Explorations in re Third World Women's leadership development, 1980 November (Report 8936)
  - Committee for Co-ordination of Investigations of the Lower Mekong Basin. Extract: "Report of the seventeenth session", 7-26 March 1962, Tokyo, Japan (Report 9098)
  - Gaer, Felice D. Fellowship programs in West European Studies and International Relations, 1975 September (Report 8114)
  - Dressner, Howard R. Fiduciary responsibilities of Trustees for investments, 1976 May (Report 9207)
  - Hill, Rey M. Final report on Iran; a possible basis for re-entry; with confidential attachment, 1964 July (Report 5075)
  - Kennedy, Roger G. The first four years, 1974 March (Report 2474)
  - Staples, Eugene S. FY 1972 Asia and the Pacific budget statement, 1971 March (Report 8929)
  - Wilhelm, Harry E. Fiscal year 1972 budget, New Delhi office, 1971 February (Report 8928)
  - Bell, David E. Follow-up to Bellagio meeting on population and agriculture: more international centers?, 1970 June (Report 4876)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation - a ten-year summary, 1951 - 1960. Consisting of fifteen charts as presented at the June 1960 meeting of the Board of Trustees (Report 5693)
  - Bell, David E. Ford Foundation activities in Finland, 1967 February (Report 9041)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation - Africa program, 1957 - 1968, July 1958 (Report 2674)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. The Ford Foundation and Canada, 1971 September (Report 9030)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. The Ford Foundation and Canada revisited, 1976 December (Report 9023)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford foundation and "dependent" organizations, 1971 September (Report 2109)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation and Foundation-supported activities in India, 1955 January (Report 2587)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation and Foundation-supported activities in India, 1959 January (Report 3345)
  - Miller, Frank J. The Ford Foundation and Indonesia: 1953-1969. Retrospect and prospect, 1969 September (Report 2627)
  - Bresnan/Green. Ford Foundation and Japan (Report 2039)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation and sub-Sahara Africa, 1970 December (Report 2774)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation and the study of China, 1971 June (Report 2771)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foùndation, Bangkok Office: report for FY 1967 and budget projections for FY 1968 (Report 9102)
  - Hilliard, John F. The Ford Foundation Caribbean Program Self-Study, 1966 September (Report 1265)
  - Heaps, David. The Ford Foundation in ex-French Territories - a critical re-assessment with some suggestions for policy reorientation, 1968 July (Report 9017)
  - Ford Foundation (ID). The Ford Foundation in Greece, 1968 March (Report 3736)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation in Japan and Korea, 1980 March (Report 9002)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation in Pakistan - January 1952 - May 1960 (Report 9104)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation in Pakistan - program report 1966 - 67., 1967 October (Report 3121)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation in the 1960s: statement of the Board of Trustees on policies, programs, and operations, 1962 July (Report 2631)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation - Indonesia. Brief data, 1967 November (Report 8969)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation management and program trends in the Fifties and Sixties, 1971 June (Report 2802)
  - Wolf, Alfred et al. Ford Foundation mission to Brazil, July - August 1959 (Report 8)
  - Wolf, Alfred et al. Ford Foundation mission to Argentina, August - Sept 1959 (Report 27)
  - Morse, Richard et al. Ford Foundation mission to Colombia June 1960 (Report 32)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation OD Self-Study (Operation Janus) -- responses from Turkey, 1966 September (Report 3053)
  - Ensminger, Douglas. The Ford Foundation Overseas Development Self-Study of the India Program, 1966 September (Report 2348)
  - Hertz, Willard J. Ford Foundation Pakistan Review Seminar: summary of discussion, 1969 September (Report 7200)
  - Kennedy, John P. The Ford Foundation program in Malaysia, 1970 March (Report 3799)
  - Ford Foundation. The Ford Foundation program in Malaysia - information paper, 1970 August (Report 2088)
  - Ford Foundation. Ford Foundation programs for women -- an information paper for the Board of Trustees, 1979 December (Report 4641)
  - Ford Foundation. Ford Foundation programs for women: plans and budgets for fiscal years 1980 and 1981, 1980 March (Report 4793)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. Ford Foundation strategy toward Western Europe, 1972 March (Report 9033)
  - Harkavy, Oscar. Ford Foundation submission to Interim Committee - Bellagio Group for meeting of 12/18/70, 1970 November (Report 9121)
  - Ford Foundation/ID The Ford Foundation's activities in Latin America and the Caribbean, 1967 September (Report 2409)
  - Gaer, Felice D. Foundation activity in Soviet and East European studies: the Soviet-East European Research Competition, 1974 July (Report 9038)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation-Administered Project: what and why?, 1972 June (Report 2839)
  - Kingsley, J. Donald. The Foundation and Israel, 1966 December (Report 8903)
  - Bell, David E. The Foundation and the less-developed countries: the decade of the seventies, 1972 March (Report 3307)
  - Staples, Eugene S. The Foundation and the world in the 1970s, 1979 February (Report 8924)
  - Ward, Frederick C. Foundation experience in Iran and Turkey, 1979 March (Report 8893)
  - Gardner, James A. The Foundation-grantee relationship, 1973 April (Report 8922)
  - (Edwards, Robert H.) The Foundation in Lebanon: July 1976, 1976 July (Report 8892)
  - Bell, David E. Foundation policies and the U.S. balance of payments, 1968 March (Report 6329)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. Foundation policies related to the U.S. balance of payments, 1968 April (Report 8964)
  - Swearer, Howard R. Foundation programs vis-a-vis East Europe and the USSR, 1970 June (Report 9036)
  - Ford Foundation. Foundation strategy for work on agricultural and resource development, 1977 (Report 8988)
  - Bell, David E. Foundation study of employment in developing countries, 1974 May (Report 9198)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation's activities in Europe, 1968 March (Report 1986)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation's concerns with peace and international security, 1974 September (Report 9199)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation's future financial condition: some numerical projections (with exhibits 1 - 10 enclosed), 1978 June (Report 4121)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation's Latin America and Caribbean program - a review and a look ahead, 1972 March (Report 4618)
  - Bundy, McGeorge. The Foundation's planning agenda for FY 1973 and beyond, 1972 July (Report 9012)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation's program concerned with the world economy - an information paper for the Board of Trustees, 1980 June (Report 5687)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation's program in Greece, 1969 September (Report 9027)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation's programs in arms control and international security, 1972 December (Report 2003)
  - Ford Foundation. The Foundation's strategy for work on population, 1977 June (Report 4140)
  - Bell, David E. Further steps toward coordination of donor support for social science research in development, 1974 May (Report 9116)
  - Germain, Adrienne. Future International Division programming on women, 1976 October (Report 8218)
  - Ford Foundation. Future investment and spending policies - a further analysis of where we are and how we might make choices for the future, 1978 March (Report 3694)
  - Bergsten, C. Fred. The future of the International Economic Order: an agenda for research, 1973 June (Report 2443)
  - Wilhelm, Harry E. Future program plans for the Office for Latin America and the Caribbean, 1970 January (Report 4655)
  - Crawley, Roy W. Future status of the Venezuelan office, 1967 September (Report 8961)
  - Sauvant, Karl P. Gaps in research on transnational enterprises, 1977 January (Report 8841)
  - Dunning, John H. Gaps of research in transnational corporations, 1977 May (Report 8843)
  - Bundy/Strasburg. The General Reserve, 1973 November (Report 4549)
  - Sutton, F. X. Ghana in May 1961 (Report 2506)
  - Faaland, Just. Government policy and planning for economic development and their relationships to social and communal stability, 1970 March (Report 3796)
  - Whiting, Basil. Grantee-grantor relations, 1973 September (Report 8921)
  - Hertz, Will. Grants to individuals - new light on an old subject, 1976 March (Report 4046)
  - Swearer, Howard L. Greek trip, 1968 May (Report 9026)
  - Bell, David E. Highlight observations on the situation in India and the Foundation's program there, 1967 December (Report 9078)
  - Ford Foundation. Historical summary of the Ford Foundation program in Burma, 1953-1962, 1965 May (Report 8456)
  - (Heaps, David). Human rights and intellectual freedom, 1975 November (Report 2256)
  - Himes, James R. ID discussion paper. Program-related investments: some notes regarding the experience of the National Affairs Division, 1969 August (Report 4444)
  - Botero, Rodrigo. The ID in Latin-America, 1980 - 1990, 1980 September (Report 8848)
  - Remenyi/Hardin. IFPRI Commentary, 1978 September (Report 9094)
  - Wells, Oris V. Improving world food situation outlook information and analysis (summary of preliminary draft), 1974 March (Report -)
    Related Materials
    See: Reports #3506 and #3507
  - Wells, Oris V. Improving world food situation outlook information and analysis. (Working paper I), 1973 November (Report 3506)
  - Wells, Oris V. Improving world food situation outlook information and analysis. (Working paper II), 1974 April (Report 3507)
  - Dahrendorf, Ralf. India - Indonesia; notes on a trip in Sept. 1977 (Report 8979)
  - Bresnan, John. Indochina, 1976 June (Report 9100)
  - Geithner, Peter. Indochinese refugees and the Ford Foundation: a report based on interviews with public and private agencies in New York and Washington, July 9-13, 1979, 1979 July (Report 8838)
  - Miller, Frank J. Indonesia, 1969, 1969 September (Report 2627)
  - Bresnan, John. Indonesia program budget: fiscal year 1971, 1970 March (Report 8926)
  - Ford Foundation. Information on Indonesia and the Ford Foundation's activities, 1967 November (Report 8969)
  - Ford Foundation. Information paper - agriculture, natural resources and related rural development, 1980 June (Report 5869)
  - Ford Foundation. Information paper - Congress for Cultural Freedom, 1967 September (Report 2784)
  - Sutton, F. X. Information paper - International Human Rights Information and Documentation Service, 1979 June (Report 4114)
  - Ford Foundation. Information paper - South and Southeast Asia, 1967 June (Report 2407)
  - Ford Foundation. Information paper for the Trustee Committee on Education and Public Policy - plans for Resources and the Environment Program, 1979 December (Report 5560)
  - Ford Foundation. Information paper for the Trustee Committee on Education and Public Policy - the Arts Program, 1980 March (Report 4710)
  - Ford Foundation. Information paper for the Trustee Committee on Education and Public Policy - the Public Policy and Social Organization Program, 1972 - 1979, 1980 March (Report 5660)
  - Ford Foundation. ID/A&P. Information paper: next steps for the Foundation concerning China, 1979 June (Report 4112)
  - Berresford, Susan et al. Information paper: programs to improve the quality of American governance, 1979 June (Report 4115)
  - Ford Foundation. Information paper. Resources and the Environment: some program options for FY 1980-81, 1978 December (Report 9112)
  - Ford Foundation. Information paper. The American University of Beirut, 1966 September (Report 2792)
  - Bell, David E. Information requested in your memo of August 20, concerning dependent organizations, 1971 September (Report 8963)
  - Berger, Morroe. Institutional aspects of development in the Middle East, 1972 February (Report 1981)
  - Sutton, F. X. Institutional collaboration and complementarities in research on income distribution and employment, 1975 January (Report 9115)
  - Ford Foundation. International Affairs Program - evaluation (1951 - 1961) and statement of current objectives and policies, 1961 December (Report 9182)
  - Discussion paper. International affairs: Un1ted Nations International School, 1964 June (Report 2942)
  - Hardin, Lowell. International agricultural centers - discussion of 1975 programs and budgets, 1974 June (Report 4981)
  - Ford Foundation. International agricultural research: commentaries on the work of the international agricultural research and training centers and their program/budget sub-missions for 1980., 1979 October (Report 8991)
  - Ford Foundation. International agricultural research: program/budget submissions of international centers for 1978 and related materials, 1977 August (Report 4546)
  - Ford Foundation. International agricultural research: program/budget submissions of international centers for 1979 and related materials, 1978 October (Report 8990)
  - Heaps, David. International Association for Cultural Freedom - a draft report, 1970 December (Report 8975)
  - Ford Foundation/OD. International cooperation in the development of Asian countries, 1956 June (Report 2761)
  - Bell, David E. The "International Division" - general shape and content, 1966 October (Report 9040)
  - Bell, David E. International Division meeting, Beirut - January 9-11, 1961 - summary notes, 1967 January (Report 8901)
  - Bell, David E. International Division submission for the December meeting, 1974 October (Report 8997)
  - Ford Foundation. The International Division's Women's Program - discussion paper, 1976 December (Report 7747)
  - Barber, Elinor G. The International Division's Women's Program - information paper, 1979 January (Report 7889)
  - Barber, Elinor G. The International Division's Women's Program - interim report, 1977 March (Report 6123)
  - Heaps. David. International Human Rights Documentation and Reference Service: Working Group meeting, London, June 22, 1979; other comments; and an assessment of progress to date, 1979 July (Report 8840)
  - Goodwin, Craufurd D. An International Institute for Policy Research, 1976 August (Report 5079)
  - Ford Foundation. International migration and refugees, 1980 March (Report 4711)
  - Ford Foundation. International portfolio diversification, 1978 March (Report 5069)